Honghao Zhang

honghaoz.com github.com/honghaoz linkedin.com/in/honghaozhang

SUMMARY

Highly experienced iOS/macOS developer who cares about UI & UX. Strong passion for the Apple ecosystem. Currently working on a high performance, cross-platform UI framework that utilizes declarative syntax, similar to SwiftUI, and is based on Apple's graphics technologies such as Core Animation, Core Graphics and Metal, etc.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Languages: Swift, Objective-C

Frameworks: UIKit/AppKit, RxSwift, Core Animation, Core Graphics, Core Text, Core Image, Metal

WORK EXPERIENCES

Robinhood - Software Engineer (iOS), Menlo Park, CA, US

Feb 2020 - Present

- Frontend tech lead on the customer support team, responsible for the roadmapping, prioritization and execution of various projects, including in-app chat, support phone call & in-app survey, etc.
- Developed various iOS infra tools, such as unit & UI testing frameworks, code generations CLI, etc.

Facebook - Software Engineer (iOS), Menlo Park, CA, US

Oct 2017 - Feb 2020

- Modularized the iOS media infra code using BUCK on Instagram Media Infra team.
- Led the development of a new media processing & uploading framework in the Instagram iOS app.

theScore - iOS Developer, Toronto, ON, Canada

Jun 2015 - Jul 2017

- Launched new designs for the Score | esports 2.0 and the Score flagship 6.0 iOS apps.
- Created & implemented various the Score iOS design system UI components.

Wattpad - iOS Developer (Intern), Toronto, ON, Canada

Aug - Dec 2014

- Developed the Wattpad editor keyboard toolbar for iPhone 6/6 Plus using Core Graphics.
- Improved the Wattpad iOS localization workflow and introduced new languages.

PROJECTS

Personal Apps

• Lickable Menu Bar (macOS) - Retro Classic Mac menu bars.

Nov 2022

• Say No to Notch (macOS) - Remove the MacBook screen "notch".

Aug 2022 Aug 2020

<u>Git Streaks for GitHub</u> (macOS) - GitHub contribution squares in menu bar.
<u>Robinhoodie</u> (macOS) - Robinhood portfolios in menu bar. (discontinued)

Jan - Dec 2020

• <u>InstaTip</u> (iOS/macOS) - Tip calculator with check image recognition.

Jul 2019

• 2048 AI (iOS) - 2048 game with AI solver.

Apr 2015

Open Source Libraries

- ChouTi a Swift framework for iOS/macOS UI components, common data structures and extensions.
- Ji an XML/HTML parser for Swift.
- AutoKeyboardScrollView a handy UIScrollView subclass to handle keyboard avoidance.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, ON, Canada

• Master of Engineering, Major in Electrical and Computer Engineering.

Sep 2013 - Jun 2015

Southeast University

Nanjing, China

• Bachelor of Engineering, Major in Electrical Engineering & Its Automation.

Sep 2008 - Jun 2012